

+351 927650410



✓ joao.andre.teixeira96@gmail.com



Ĭſ⋒ @joãoteixeira96



https://github.com/joaoteixeira96



Cybersecurity



PROFILE

Since I was a kid, I always wanted to catch bad guys, but in a smart way! So cybersecurity was the deal. I'm a curious person with team spirit, openminded and eager to learn, having several years of experience in programming and security gained through personal, academic, and company projects. Looking for a role where I can grow and continue to learn from experienced people.

EDUCATIONAL

NOVA College of Science and Technology

Master of Science in Computer Science.

• Attended from Sept. 2019 to Sept. 2021, specializing in computer network, cryptography, network security and distributed systems.

NOVA College of Science and Technology

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science.

• Attended from Sept. 2015 to April 2019.

SKILLS

Knowledge Areas

- Vulnerability Management.
- Risk Assessment.
- Application Security.

Programming/Web Development

• Java, Python, SQL, C, Kotlin, JavaScript/ReactJS, HTML/CSS.

Tools/Frameworks/CTF

• Kali linux, Metasploit, Nessus, BurpSuite, Nmap, ZAP, Wireshark, John, Hydra, sqlmap, TOR, Docker, Azure, Git, OWASP, NIST, OSSTMM, MITRE ATT&CK.

EXPERIENCE

Security Delivery Associate

Accenture Portugal | July 2021 to present.

- Vulnerability Management
 - Assess, validate the risk and prioritize remediation of the vulnerabilities.
 - o Coordinate responsibilities with the different project teams.
 - Create a monthly executive report.
- Application Security
 - Application testing and conducting security assessment for web applications using SCA, SAST and DAST scan tools & manual penetration
 - Executive report & presentation of the findings.

Full Stack Developer Intern

EInnovator - Enterprise Middleware, LTD | Oct. 2018 to Feb. 2019.

- Developed a microservice solution using Spring Framework that allowed companies and employees to review, edit or revoke product contracts.
- · Agile methodology (Jira).

Member of the organization committee

NLNF - FCT NOVA IT Club | Sept. 2018 to July 2019.

• Organized Talks, Workshops and a 2-day Hackathon.

Member of the organization committee

JORTEC - FCT NOVA IT Club | Sept. 2017 to July 2018.

• Organized Workshops and a 3-day Hackathon.

PROJECTS

Thesis - Strengthening of Tor Against Traffic Correlation with K-Anonymity Input Circuits

• Built a mechanism to protect Tor users against traffic correlation attacks, using combined techniques: Kanonymity routing strategy and overlaying traffic morphing